Hello everyone, and welcome back
to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine, and today Marco and
I have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right, it's a new year, and so we
have a lesson for you where we are going to
make new decisions and have a
new opportunity in the new year, right?
That's right, so the new year is the
time to change parts of your life, maybe.
So that's what we're
going to talk about today,
let's listen to this dialogue three times,
and when we come back we'll be talking
about the words and
phrases in the dialogue.
Now that it's the new year, I've
decided to turn over a new leaf.
Yeah, you finally decided
to wipe the slate clean.
You got it, I have a new job, I'm
living in a new city with new friends.
This is my opportunity to make some
small changes in the way I live my life.
So what are you going to do?
Take up an art class or something?
Well, first of all, I've
decided to stop smoking.
It's not that I'm pinching
pennies or anything,
it's just that I've been smoking since
I was 16, and I think it's time to stop.
I'm with you on that one.
Anything else you're planning on doing?
One last thing.
I've decided to come out of the closet.
It's about time.
All right, we're back,
and so if you notice,
the dialogue has
actually a lot of really,
really rich phrases in
there. So today, we're
going to change
the format a little bit,
and we're going to do fluency
builder in two different sections.
So starting out with the first
one on fluency builder part one.
Fluency builder.
So the new year, we think about
new things, changing things.
We have a great phrase in English to
describe starting fresh, starting anew.
And we say, "Turn
over a new leaf.
" Okay, so you turn over
a new leaf. So that means
that you are going to maybe
make a radical change, right?
Some completely new.
That's right. So if you
think about it, it's a
new chapter in your life
for a new adventure or
something like that. Maybe
you're going to quit your job.
Turn over a new
leaf. Start a new job.
Okay. So you can say,
I'm going to turn over
a new leaf or Sarah
turned over a new leaf
and quit smoking. Let's turn
over a new leaf and forget the past.
There we go. All right.
So to turn over a new
leaf, so just imagine
that you have a leaf
on the ground and you turn
it over and it's nice and clean.
All right. And talking
about cleanliness,
our second phrase is
to wipe the slate clean.
Okay. When I think about this
phrase, I think about a chalkboard.
Okay. So a slate
is like a chalkboard
and all of the things that you've done
good and bad are on that chalkboard.
And to wipe the slate clean means to
erase those words, erase those things.
So perhaps Marco and I fight all
the time and we're angry at each other.
Finally, I say, listen, Marco, let's wipe
the slate clean. Let's forget the past.
Let's forget the things
we said and start again.
Start a new leaf to wipe
the slate clean is to just
start over, you know,
just to erase everything.
Let's forget about it
and start over. Exactly.
All right. And so
we're starting over and
his friend is asking you
decided to wipe the slate clean.
And the friend said, you got it.
You got what? What it? What is it? English
in English. We love the word it. Yeah.
Well, in this case, you
got it means you're right.
Exactly. You understand
what I'm talking about.
Okay. So if you agree with
me or I understand what
you're talking about,
you would say you got it.
You got it. You
got it. All right.
So I'm trying to explain to you
maybe Marco something very difficult.
Like, you know, if you add four and 10,
you get 14. But what if you add 10 more?
It's 24. You got
it. All right. Okay.
So he understands math. Yes.
Okay. So that's the way you would use.
You got it. It's really
popular phrase.
I mean, you can use
it and pretty much
anything, not only if
you're right, but also if
somebody agrees with it or
you promise something, right?
So are you going
to pick me up today?
Yeah, you got it. Okay. So
it's a way to agree or to show
that you're saying
yes. Yes. Okay.
So why don't we listen to our
dialogue again? And we'll come
back shortly to look at the fluency builder
part two. Now that it's the new year,
I've decided to
turn over a new leaf.
Yeah, you finally decided
to white the slate clean.
You got it. I have a
new job. I'm living in a
new city with new friends.
This is my opportunity
to make some small changes
in the way I live my life.
So what are you going
to do? Take up an art
class or something? Well,
first of all, I've decided
to stop smoking. It's not that
I'm pinching pennies or anything.
It's just that I've been
smoking since I was 16.
And I think it's time to stop.
I'm with you on that
one. Anything else you're
planning on doing? One last
thing. I've decided to come
out of the closet. It's
about time. All right.
We're back. So now let's
continue with our fluency builder.
And well, they kept talking.
And the guy mentioned that
he's going to stop smoking,
but it's not because he is pinching
pennies. Oh, pinching. That sounds painful.
Right. Okay, pinching
is something you do,
especially when you're a
child. You squeeze the skin
pinch. And it hurts. So to pinch really
is the whole something with two fingers.
To pinch pennies means
to try to spend very,
very, very little money.
Okay. So if we say,
if I say, hey, Marco, you
want to go to dinner night?
There's this really
nice Italian place.
It's a little expensive,
but I can. I'm sorry.
I'm really pinching pennies these
days because I'm kind of broke.
So maybe we'll go
somewhere cheaper.
Yeah. So actually
pennies are one cent,
one cent coin, right? They're called
pennies in the United States. That's right.
And it's the smallest kind of
money that we have in America.
So if you're pinching pennies,
if you're saving pennies,
it means you really
don't have much money.
You really, really savings,
right? Okay. So pinching pennies.
So he decided to quit
smoking and his friend agreed
with him and said,
you know what?
I'm with you on that one. Okay.
So you quit smoking, Marco.
And I quit smoking. I'm
with you. And now I think
it's a good idea. If I'm
with you on that one, it
means I, I agree with
you. You're, you're doing
the right thing. So you can
say, I'm with you on that one.
Or you can just say, you
know what, I'm with you.
Do it. Or I'm with you. I agree.
Or I'm with you. I
support your decision.
So you are going to go sky
diving in a couple of weeks.
That means you're going
to jump out of an airplane.
I'm not with you on that one.
I think it's okay for you,
but I would not want to do it.
All right. Right. So you can do
it in that way or just anything.
You support somebody's decision.
I'm with you. I'm with
you on that one. Exactly.
All right. And our last phrase
to come out of the closet.
So who's, who's in the closet?
Why is somebody
hiding in the closet? Okay.
Someone's not really hiding
in the closet. This is a phrase
we use to describe someone
who is gay or lesbian,
who is, who has a secret
about being gay or lesbian.
So when they come
out of the closet,
they're telling their
friends and family for the
first time that this is
what this is, how they feel.
So it's basically a phrase
that's kind of a metaphor
to say, you know what,
I'm going to tell everyone
that I am gay or lesbian.
Right. That's right.
Well, it's because in
English oftentimes a closet
is a place where we
keep secrets. Okay.
And so to come out of the closet
means to share your secrets with people.
So sometimes in English, you say, you
have skeletons in the closet. That's right.
This is a little different.
Maybe I killed someone.
And it's a skeleton in my
closet. It's a secret that I keep.
But a skeleton in
your closet can also
be a very big secret. Like
you were once married
and you never told anyone. Yeah. Or I have,
I have two kids and I never told you guys.
Right. So those are the
skeletons in the closet.
But in this case, it's to
come out of the closet.
And that's always related
to telling somebody
for the first time that
you are gay or lesbian.
That's right. And we
don't say it about being
straight, which is
the opposite, which is
man, men who love women
and women who love men.
You don't say it about
coming out of the closet there.
You say it about
being gay or lesbian.
Okay. So very interesting.
And so I think we should
listen to this dialogue
for the last time
and we'll be back to
talk a little bit more.
Now that it's the new
year, I've decided to turn
over a new leaf. Yeah? You finally decided
to wipe the slate clean. You got it.
I have a new job. I'm living
in a new city with new friends.
This is my opportunity to make some
small changes in the way I live my life.
So what are you going to do?
Take up an art closet or something?
Well, first of all, I've
decided to stop smoking.
It's not that I'm pinching
pennies or anything.
It's just that I've been smoking since
I was 16. And I think it's time to stop.
I'm with you on that one.
Anything else you're planning on doing?
One last thing. I've decided to
come out of the closet. It's about time.
All right, we're back.
So this is very interesting.
And these phrases are so common because
if you have a fight with somebody, you say,
you know what, let's
just wipe the slate clean
and start all over again
or just turn over a new leaf.
Let's stop fighting.
And especially in
New Years, right? Everyone
makes a promise to start fresh.
That's right. Well,
the new year you can
use a new calendar. You can
take a fresh perspective on your life.
It's refreshing.
And I think it's good that we
do this. We evaluate the things
that make us happy and
we evaluate the things
that make us unhappy.
And part of that means
turning over a new
leaf. Part of it also means
apologizing to people or trying to make
the relationships in your life healthier.
And I think it's very
healthy to the person in
this dialogue says,
"Listen, I'm finally going to
come out of the closet.
I'm going to be honest
with my friends and
family." And that's really
interesting because as
we said, to come out of
the closet is a phrase
used in English and mostly
related only in this
context. So you might see it
in TV shows or in a
movie. But it's an interesting
topic still debatable
all over the world about,
you know, gay marriages
and things like that.
That's right. So we're
curious about your New
Year's resolutions. Are
you going to be wiping
any slates clean? Are
you going to be doing
anything differently this
year? Let us know on our
website, englishpod.com.
We look forward to hearing
from you and until next
time. Bye, everyone. Bye.